[Sharp Blade in the Snow]
[نصل حاد في الثلج]
[Episode 19]
[الحلقة 19]
I thought
ظننت
Xiqi forced you
أجبرك Xiqi
into this political marriage.
في هذا الزواج السياسي.
But now...
لكن الآن...
The Queen of Mocheng is quite beautiful.
ملكة موتشنغ جميلة جداً.
But I'm also good-looking.
لكنني أيضاً وسيم.
She will marry into Xiqi.
ستتزوج من شيقي.
Why don't you consider me instead, Stone King of Hell?
لماذا لا تفكر بي بدلاً من ذلك، يا ملك الجحيم الحجري؟
You got me out of jail
لقد أخرجتني من السجن
and gave me freedom,
ومنحني الحرية،
I'll help you out of this situation
سأساعدك في الخروج من هذا الموقف
and give you freedom in return.
وأمنحك الحرية في المقابل.
This marriage isn’t something to play around with.
هذا الزواج ليس شيئاً يُستهان به.
The Young Master of Xiqi
سيد شي تشي الشاب
has to return with me to Mocheng
يجب أن يعود معي إلى موتشنغ
as the Imperial Consort
بصفتها القرينة الإمبراطورية
to form an alliance through marriage.
لتكوين تحالف من خلال الزواج.
This is the only way to protect both cities.
هذه هي الطريقة الوحيدة لحماية المدينتين.
Princess Xin Miao is brave.
الأميرة شين مياو شجاعة.
Young Master Xin Yao is wise.
السيد الشاب شين ياو حكيم.
The Xin family is virtuous and kind.
عائلة شين عائلة فاضلة ولطيفة.
Even if it costs my life,
حتى لو كلفني ذلك حياتي،
I will never let
لن أسمح أبداً
Meng Wu take control of Mocheng.
يتولى منغ وو السيطرة على موتشنغ.
For Xiqi
لشيتشي
and Mocheng,
وفي موتشنغ،
we must do this.
يجب علينا فعل ذلك.
Stone King of Hell, you are a righteous man.
يا ملك الجحيم الحجري، أنت رجل صالح.
I hope you
أتمنى أن
can prioritize the greater good.
يمكن إعطاء الأولوية للمصلحة العامة.
Dongli has fallen.
لقد سقط دونجلي.
I understand the pain of losing one's homeland,
أتفهم ألم فقدان الوطن،
and the suffering of exile.
ومعاناة المنفى.
Li.
الذي - التي.
Since you carry such righteousness,
بما أنك تحمل مثل هذا البر،
I won't stop you.
لن أمنعك.
I'll escort you back to Mocheng.
سأرافقك إلى موتشنغ.
He is truly remarkable
إنه شخص رائع حقاً
and broad-minded.
وذو عقلية منفتحة.
Since you two broke up anyway,
بما أنكما انفصلتما على أي حال،
what about giving him to me?
ماذا لو أعطيته لي؟
Stone King of Hell is renowned
يُعرف ملك الحجر في الجحيم
in Xiqi.
في شي تشي.
We can negotiate.
يمكننا التفاوض.
If he can't marry me, recruitment works too.
إذا لم يستطع الزواج بي، فإن التوظيف حلٌّ أيضاً.
I think you have no chance.
أعتقد أنه ليس لديك أي فرصة.
But anyway,
على أي حال،
I'm quite satisfied
أنا راضٍ تماماً
with my wife.
مع زوجتي.
Now you're me, and I'm you.
أنت الآن أنا، وأنا أنت.
She
هي
is my wife.
هي زوجتي.
I thought
ظننت
she was pushed by circumstances,
لقد دفعتها الظروف إلى ذلك.
and forced into marriage.
وأُجبرت على الزواج.
But it turns out this was all her plan.
لكن اتضح أن كل هذا كان من خطتها.
Stone King of Hell,
ملك الحجر في الجحيم،
Yun Zhan,
يون زان,
which one is your true identity?
أيٌّ منها هويتك الحقيقية؟
Both are.
كلاهما كذلك.
Yet not entirely.
لكن ليس تماماً.
I like them both.
أحبهما كليهما.
Why are you so determined to die?
لماذا أنت مصمم على الموت؟
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
If you return to Mocheng
إذا عدت إلى موتشنغ
and marry the Young Master of Xiqi,
وتتزوج من السيد الشاب لشي تشي،
at that time,
في ذلك الوقت،
the Phoenix Incense formula,
تركيبة بخور فينيكس،
the Phoenix Seal,
ختم العنقاء،
and the black jade,
واليشم الأسود،
will all appear.
سيظهر الجميع.
Meng Wu
منغ وو
will certainly try her best that day
ستبذل قصارى جهدها بالتأكيد في ذلك اليوم
to kill you.
لأقتلك.
You want to trade your life
تريد أن تضحي بحياتك
for Xiqi's power.
من أجل قوة شي تشي.
Utilizing your marriage,
باستخدام زواجك،
you want the Young Master of Xiqi
تريد السيد الشاب لشي تشي
to eliminate Meng Wu for you.
للقضاء على منغ وو نيابةً عنك.
Am I right?
هل أنا على صواب؟
You've seen through everything.
لقد كشفت كل شيء.
You set up this trap yourself
لقد نصبت هذا الفخ بنفسك
and put yourself in danger.
وتعريض نفسك للخطر.
How am I supposed
كيف يُفترض بي
to save you?
لإنقاذك؟
Mocheng
في المنتصف
is the land
هي الأرض
our Feng family has protected for generations.
لقد حافظت عائلة فينغ على الحماية لأجيال.
Protecting Mocheng
حماية المدينة
and its people
وشعبها
is my duty.
هذا واجبي.
That's all
هذا كل شيء
I care about.
أنا أهتم بـ.
The Xin siblings are kind-hearted.
الأشقاء شين طيبو القلب.
They won't make things difficult for the new heir,
لن يجعلوا الأمور صعبة على الوريث الجديد،
Feng Ling'er.
فنغ لينغ إير.
I will always be with you.
سأكون معك دائماً.
We will get through this.
سنتجاوز هذا الأمر.
So when do you plan
متى تخطط إذن؟
to tell me the truth,
لأقول الحقيقة،
Little Stone？
حجر صغير؟
You did recognize me.
لقد تعرفت عليّ.
You're the heir of Mocheng.
أنت وريث موتشنغ.
Why did you lie to me
لماذا كذبت علي؟
that you were a wandering beggar?
أنك كنت متسولاً متجولاً؟
Your lie hurt me deeply.
كذبتك آلمتني بشدة.
You betrayed me once,
لقد خنتني مرة،
and I deceived you once.
وقد خدعتك مرة.
Now we're even.
الآن تعادلنا.
The trip back to Mocheng is dangerous.
رحلة العودة إلى موتشنغ خطيرة.
This time, I must escort you back myself.
هذه المرة، يجب أن أرافقك بنفسي.
Don't say such foolish words.
لا تتفوه بمثل هذه الكلمات الحمقاء.
In Mocheng,
في موتشنغ،
you're considered dead.
أنت تعتبر ميتاً.
What identity will you use
ما هي الهوية التي ستستخدمها؟
to return to the palace with me?
هل تعود معي إلى القصر؟
The powerful Stone King of Hell
ملك الحجر الجبار
came back from the dead.
عاد من الموت.
That's not impossible.
هذا ليس مستحيلاً.
Stone King of Hell
ملك الجحيم الحجري
failed in his assassination attempt
فشل في محاولته للاغتيال
and would be escorted back to Mocheng
وسيتم اصطحابهم إلى موتشنغ
to await your judgment.
في انتظار حكمكم.
[Fengling Hall]
[قاعة فينغلينغ]
Ling'er, you looks pale.
لينغير، تبدين شاحبة.
How are you recently?
كيف حالك مؤخراً؟
Aunt,
عمة،
why did it take you so long to see me?
لماذا استغرق الأمر كل هذا الوقت لرؤيتي؟
I've been confined for many days.
لقد كنت محتجزاً لعدة أيام.
Nobody treats me as their master now.
لم يعد أحد يعاملني كسيّده الآن.
The Queen has married far away into Xiqi.
تزوجت الملكة من شي تشي البعيدة.
I've been occupied with matters to attend to.
لقد كنت مشغولاً ببعض الأمور التي يجب عليّ الاهتمام بها.
I meant to ask you to assist me,
كنتُ أقصد أن أطلب منك مساعدتي،
but...
لكن...
I planned to make a scene
كنت أخطط لإثارة ضجة.
on the departure day
في يوم المغادرة
and refused to go to Xiqi even if I killed myself
ورفضت الذهاب إلى شي تشي حتى لو قتلت نفسي
to make it difficult for Feng Li.
لجعل الأمر صعباً على فنغ لي.
But she confined me.
لكنها حبستني.
I'm not allowed to
لا يُسمح لي بـ
leave my palace.
اخرج من قصري.
She still has the nerve to go for the political marriage herself.
لا تزال لديها الجرأة على الإقدام على الزواج السياسي بنفسها.
She is the dignified Queen of Mocheng.
إنها ملكة موشينغ المهيبة.
But she brought such shame upon herself.
لكنها جلبت على نفسها عاراً كبيراً.
She is truly unworthy of being a member of the Feng family.
إنها حقاً لا تستحق أن تكون فرداً من عائلة فينغ.
Li has wandered since childhood.
تجول لي منذ طفولته.
Life has never been easy for her.
لم تكن الحياة سهلة بالنسبة لها قط.
When survival is at stake,
عندما يكون البقاء على المحك،
who will care about dignity?
من سيهتم بالكرامة؟
She may have no shame
ربما لا تشعر بالخجل
but Mocheng does,
لكن موتشنغ يفعل ذلك،
and so do we, descendants of the Feng family!
ونحن كذلك، أحفاد عائلة فينغ!
Aunt.
عمة.
Be good, Ling'er.
كن بخير يا لينغ إير.
Now that Feng Li is gone,
والآن بعد رحيل فينغ لي،
I will take care of you.
سأعتني بك.
We are members of the royal clan.
نحن أعضاء في العائلة المالكة.
As long as she is the Queen,
طالما أنها الملكة،
I am inferior to her.
أنا أقل شأناً منها.
Aunt.
عمة.
If you don't want to be a bird in a cage,
إذا كنت لا تريد أن تكون كطائر في قفص،
you might as well take a chance.
ربما من الأفضل أن تغامر.
The half Tiger Tally your mother left you
نصف نمر تركه لك والدتك
before she died
قبل وفاتها
can command the palace guards.
بإمكانه إصدار الأوامر لحراس القصر.
With the Tiger Tally,
مع إحصاء النمور،
you can break the deadlock.
يمكنك كسر الجمود.
The Tiger Tally
إحصاء النمور
was taken by Feng Li before she left.
تم التقاط الصورة بواسطة فينغ لي قبل مغادرتها.
What a pity.
يا للأسف.
I thought you were
ظننت أنك
a clever person.
شخص ذكي.
Aunt.
عمة.
I came to see you before I leave.
جئت لرؤيتك قبل أن أغادر.
This might be the last time
قد تكون هذه هي المرة الأخيرة
we sisters see each other.
نحن الأخوات نرى بعضنا البعض.
Your Majesty, you are sending me away for a political marriage.
يا صاحب الجلالة، أنت ترسلني للزواج من أجل زواج سياسي.
So, no one will be in your way anymore, right?
إذن، لن يقف أحد في طريقك بعد الآن، أليس كذلك؟
I didn't come for small talk.
لم آتِ من أجل أحاديث عابرة.
I want you to give me something important,
أريدك أن تعطيني شيئاً مهماً،
your mother's Tiger Tally.
إحصائيات النمور الخاصة بوالدتك.
I knew it.
كنت أعرف.
You didn't come with good intentions.
لم تأتِ بنوايا حسنة.
So, you're after the Tiger Tally.
إذن، أنت تسعى وراء إحصاء النمور.
My mother was the former Guardian General.
كانت والدتي هي الحارس العام السابق.
By tradition, both the Tiger Tally
بحسب التقاليد، فإن كلاً من إحصاء النمور
and the general's position
وموقف الجنرال
should be passed to me.
ينبغي أن يتم تمريرها إليّ.
You refused to grant me a title
لقد رفضت منحي لقباً
and are sending me far away to Xiqi.
ويرسلونني بعيداً إلى شي تشي.
Isn't it just to
أليس من العدل أن
eliminate me as a threat?
هل تريدون التخلص مني كتهديد؟
So, you know your mother was the
إذن، أنت تعلم أن والدتك كانت
Guardian General, hugh?
الحارس العام، هيو؟
You’re nothing but a spoiled fool!
أنت لست سوى أحمق مدلل!
How can you be a daughter of our family?
كيف يمكنكِ أن تكوني ابنة عائلتنا؟
How dare you have the nerve to criticize me?
كيف تجرؤ على انتقادي؟
Do you think you’re any better?
هل تعتقد أنك أفضل حالاً؟
Everyone in Mocheng
جميع سكان موتشنغ
knows that you are indulging in luxury and pleasure,
يعلم أنك تنغمس في الرفاهية والمتعة،
and living in complete debauchery.
ويعيشون في حالة من الفجور التام.
Everyone calls you "Demon Lord" behind your back.
الجميع يناديك بـ"سيد الشياطين" من وراء ظهرك.
If Aunt hadn't taken you in
لو لم تكن عمتك قد استقبلتك
and managed everything for you,
وتولت إدارة كل شيء نيابةً عنك،
would you even be alive now?
هل كنت ستكون على قيد الحياة الآن؟
How dare you hit me?
كيف تجرؤ على ضربي؟
Yes.
نعم.
Wake up!
استيقظ!
Use your brain
استخدم عقلك
and think carefully.
وفكر ملياً.
I had been exiled for so many years.
لقد عشت في المنفى لسنوات عديدة.
I couldn't even pay respects to my mom
لم أستطع حتى أن أقدم واجب العزاء لأمي
on her death anniversary.
في ذكرى وفاتها.
What real power do I have?
ما هي القوة الحقيقية التي أمتلكها؟
Think about who it is
فكر في من هو
that refuses to grant you a title.
الذي يرفض منحك لقباً.
Why does Xiqi want a marriage alliance now?
لماذا تريد شي تشي تحالف زواج الآن؟
The one who fears you
الذي يخشاك
and wants to send you away
ويريد أن يصرفك
is your dear Aunt.
إنها عمتك العزيزة.
Impossible!
مستحيل!
Aunt loves me the most.
عمتي تحبني أكثر من أي شخص آخر.
It can't be.
لا يمكن أن يكون ذلك.
Ling'er.
لينغ.
You are kind-hearted and innocent.
أنت طيب القلب وبريء.
After so many years by her side,
بعد سنوات عديدة قضيناها بجانبها،
of course you won't believe me
بالطبع لن تصدقني
when I tell you these things.
عندما أخبرك بهذه الأشياء.
Let's make a bet.
لنراهن.
Do you dare?
هل تجرؤ؟
What trick are you plotting now?
ما هي الحيلة التي تخطط لها الآن؟
This bet concerns
هذا الرهان يتعلق
Mocheng and its future.
موتشنغ ومستقبلها.
You just want to take
أنت تريد فقط أن تأخذ
my Tiger Tally
حصتي من النمور
and send me far away to Xiqi.
وأرسلني بعيداً إلى شي تشي.
Why bother lying?
لماذا عناء الكذب؟
I know very well what's going on.
أعرف جيداً ما يجري.
The marriage alliance is real.
تحالف الزواج حقيقي.
Someone will go to Xiqi.
سيذهب أحدهم إلى شي تشي.
But you're not the one.
لكنك لست الشخص المناسب.
Then, who else?
إذن، من أيضاً؟
Me.
أنا.
Hide the Tiger Tally.
أخفِ إحصاء النمر.
Meng Wu will come to ask you for it.
سيأتي منغ وو ليطلبها منك.
You can tell her
يمكنك إخبارها
that I took it.
أنني أخذته.
If she still treats you the same as before,
إذا كانت لا تزال تعاملك بنفس الطريقة السابقة،
then I lose.
ثم أخسر.
What if I win?
ماذا لو فزت؟
If you win,
إذا فزت،
with the Tiger Tally in hand,
ومع وجود إحصائية النمور في اليد،
you can overthrow me
بإمكانك أن تطيح بي
and take my place anytime.
ويمكنك أن تحل مكاني في أي وقت.
She's mad.
إنها غاضبة.
She's asking me to rebel against her?
هل تطلب مني أن أتمرد عليها؟
Now that the Queen is absent,
الآن وقد غابت الملكة،
with the Phoenix Seal in my possession,
وبوجود ختم العنقاء في حوزتي،
I am in charge of governing Mocheng.
أنا المسؤول عن إدارة مدينة موتشنغ.
If you have the Tiger Tally but refuse to hand it over,
إذا كنت تمتلك سجلّ النمور ولكنك ترفض تسليمه،
that would be defying orders.
سيكون ذلك بمثابة عصيان للأوامر.
I...
أنا...
Everything I said is true.
كل ما قلته صحيح.
Before Feng Li left,
قبل مغادرة فينغ لي،
she took the Tiger Tally.
أخذت إحصاء النمور.
Aunt, look,
يا عمتي، انظري،
she left my palace in chaos.
لقد تركت قصري في حالة من الفوضى.
Ling'er.
لينغ.
You're merely an insignificant clan daughter.
أنتِ مجرد ابنة عشيرة تافهة.
Even with the Tiger Tally, what could you possibly do?
حتى مع وجود إحصائية النمر، ما الذي يمكنك فعله؟
The Tiger Tally
إحصاء النمور
is nothing but a pile of scrap metal to you.
إنها ليست سوى كومة من الخردة المعدنية بالنسبة لك.
It's not scrap.
إنها ليست خردة.
It's proof of my mother's military achievements.
إنه دليل على إنجازات والدتي العسكرية.
You are really like your mother,
أنت تشبه والدتك كثيراً،
strong-willed and fierce.
قوية الإرادة وشرسة.
However,
لكن،
she's dead.
لقد ماتت.
If you fail to choose wisely,
إذا فشلت في الاختيار بحكمة،
I'll kill you.
سأقتلك.
You...
أنت...
Even if you kill me,
حتى لو قتلتني،
I can't make it appear out of nowhere.
لا أستطيع أن أجعلها تظهر من العدم.
Aunt.
عمة.
You know I rely on you the most.
أنت تعلم أنني أعتمد عليك أكثر من أي شخص آخر.
How could you say such hurtful words?
كيف تجرؤ على قول مثل هذه الكلمات المؤذية؟
If I really had the Tiger Tally,
لو كان لديّ بالفعل إحصاء النمور،
wouldn't I have used it
ألم أكن لأستخدمه؟
to deal with Feng Li?
كيف أتعامل مع فنغ لي؟
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
your confinement
حبسك
will remain.
سيبقى.
Stay in your mansion.
ابقَ في قصرك.
Feng Li was right after all.
كان فنغ لي محقاً في النهاية.
What should I do now?
ماذا عليّ أن أفعل الآن؟